henisha rathod

Lead Engineer, +1 602-702-9523, henisha.rathod@gmail.com

Location Total Work Experience

Mesa, Arizona United States 9 years

Work History

Lead Engineer, WageWatch Inc. (Sep 2015)

Senior Software Engineer, Tatvasoft Pvt Ltd. (Apr 2012 - Nov 2014)

Junior Software Engineer, Nyusoft Solutions (Apr 2011 - Apr 2012)

Skills

• ado.net • ajax • asp.net

• c (programming language) • c++ • cascading style sheets

• crystal reports • c-sharp • database

• electronic commerce

Education

AES Institute of Computer Studies , Ahmedabad, India Master's Degree

 $\textbf{Som-Lalit institute of Computer Application, Ahmedabad , India} \ \textbf{Bachelor's Degree}$

HENISHA RATHOD

C: 6027029523 | henisha.rathod@gmail.com

PROFILE:

7+ years of experience in Analysis, Design, development and Implementation of distributed & web applications using .NET technologies.

Extensive Hands-on Knowledge and Experience in Azure stack, MVC, C#, VB, ASP.Net, SQL Server, Web Services, WCF, WebAPI, Angular JS, Angular 2, .Net Core, HTML5, CSS3.

Strong Technical background, excellent analytical ability, Practical experience in architecting the solution and implementing the system from scratch.

Good Communication skills, Interpersonal skills, Flexible, Fast learner and ability to work effectively independently and also part of a team.

FDUCATION

Masters in Computer Science - Year 2010

AES Institute of Computer Studies , Ahmedabad, India

Bachelors in Computer Science - Year 2007

Som-Lalit institute of Computer Application, Ahmedabad , India

EXPERIENCE:

WageWatch Inc. - Lead Engineer - Sep-2015 to Present

End to End responsible for developing and managing core revenue generating web applications. This platform is built upon .NET technologies using C#.Net, MVC 5, WebAPI, AngularJS, AJAX, Kendo Controls, NetCore under Visual Studio 2015,2017,2019 environment.

Designed and implemented solutions to Core company application platform that brings revenue.

Developed and deployed company's cloud-based infrastructure using Microsoft Azure services.

Provided application/technology specific consultation and trainings to team members and client.

Responsible for all aspects of applications including requirement analysis, solution design, implementation, deployment.

Tatvasoft Pvt Ltd. - Senior Software Engineer - Apr-2012 to Nov-2014

Worked in multiple roles and delivered many projects as below.

Cloudiway:

An Email Migration tool that enables migration of email accounts between different services. It migrate Contacts, Emails, Calendar, Task information of source account into destination account. It supports different messaging systems (Google Apps, Office 365, Lotus Notes, IMAP, Exchange, or Thunderbird), and enables you to migrate from both mail clients and mail servers. An administrator can trigger the migration or can let the individual user migrate at a time to suit them.

Deployed in Azure with middleware components using c#.

Job portal:

A Multi-language employment web application that helps employers and future employees to post and apply for job. It is developed using ASP.Net (FrontEnd), C# (Middle Core) and SQL Server (BackEnd).

Uman Ubase:

Job portal (as above) however it was developed with MVC framework.

Material Management:

This system used for Companies for Material Management in large scale.

Application is developed in MVC 5 with Subsonic at the data layer.

Used RDLC report for reporting and WCF service for database operations.

KitKat

It allows internal Project, Device and Employee Management.

Developed in MVC5, bootstrap with Entity Framework at the data layer.

Nyusoft Solutions. - Junior Software Engineer - Apr-2011 to Apr-2012

Worked in multiple roles and delivered many projects as below.

E-Drive Autos

WebApplication that Offers car shoppers a quick and easy means of researching and purchasing deep-discounted vehicles without the hassle or negotiations that are common when purchasing from a car lot

Integrated the Third party Tool (CARFAX for Vehicle Summary Report), Used NADA web services for checking the vehicle price

Mama s Restaurant Supply

Project had rich features and a capability that created a powerful e-commerce store which provided international market for users' products and anyone could buy those products

Administrators were able to define products/services, their attributes, map to any categories, define schemes for promotion of the products; other details of the products could also be defined

An interactive and rich environment was served to the users for browsing and purchasing products/services of their interest

Architected, designed and developed the system in 3 tiers

Developed the front end using ASP.Net

Developed Serviced middleware components using C#

Designed and developed the database and wrote stored procedures

Online shopping using PayPal Direct and Refund Functionality

Tranpost:

Architected, designed and developed the system in MVC3

Developed the front end using Razor View

Developed Mode and Controller components using C#

Designed and developed the database and wrote stored procedures

Online shopping using PayPal Direct

Seatram:

Content Management System developed in ASP.Net and C#

KEY TECHNICAL SKILLS:

Web Technologies

ASP.NET, MVC, AJAX, AngularJS, Windows Azure, AJAX, .Net Core

Web Services, WCF, WebAPI

Programming Languages

C#, VB, C, C++

Database

MS Access, SQL server 2005/2008/2010/2012

MySQL, Oracle, MONGODB, Entity Framework, Linq

Scripting and Markup

JavaScript, Jquery, CSS, HTML, XML, JSON, TypeScript

Source Code management

TFS, SVN, GIT

Reporting Tools

Crystal Reports, RDLC, Telerik Reports Other Skills

Agile (SCRUM) Application development methodologies

Telerik Controls, Kendo Controls